AFRASIYAB (AFROKK) KHAN

hi@afrokk.dev | LinkedIn.com/in/afrasiyab-k | GitHub.com/Afrokk | www.afrokk.dev

SUMMARY

Upcoming **Software Engineering** grad with 7 years of experience in the tech industry, **managing a 1.7M subs YT channel**, **former founder of a tech news website**, and an avid freelancer with **works featured** in **Forbes**, **Uber**, and **more**.

EXPERIENCE

Creative Design Manager

March 2019 - Present

Remote

YouTube (@xeetechcare)

- Directed a thriving **1.7 million subscribers** YouTube channel to produce **tech** content for a worldwide audience.
- Managed partnerships with renowned brands including Samsung, Google, Chevrolet, and more across diverse sectors.
 Produced a content library of over 2,000 videos showcasing the latest in technology, spanning smartphones,
- computers, and electric vehicles, garnering an impressive 5 million monthly views.
 Implemented SEO strategies to elevate channel visibility resulting in up to 40% increase in views from high CPM regions.

Lead Teaching Assistant

January 2022 - Present

uWindsor School of Computer Science

Windsor, ON

- Mentored 100s of students in four major Computer Science courses including C, OOP with Java and OS Programming.
 Conducted workshops with over 200 students to teach Computer Science tools, including C, Java, SQL, along with
- Conducted **workshops** with over **200** students to teach Computer Science tools, including **C**, **Java**, **SQL**, along with **multithreading**, and **network socket** concepts.

Co-founderGeeksULTD
May 2016 - February 2019
Malaysia

- Established and piloted GeeksULTD.COM, a technology/gaming-based website for 3 years.
 - Accelerated website load times by optimizing JavaScript & CSS files and integrating CDN technologies resulting in up to 2x faster load times.
 - Published over 550 articles and reviews related to computers, technology, and gaming, for over 100K monthly viewers.
 - Collaborated with Samsung, Logitech, MSi, and more to publish over 30 product reviews and editorials.

EDUCATION

University of Windsor

Windsor, ON

Bachelors in Computer Science, Minor in Communications, Media & Film | GPA: 3.9/4.0 | President's List

PROJECTS

BlazeGuard | TypeScript, React, NextJS 13, Express, Python, mySQL | GitHub

September 2023

- Developed a full-stack web app enabling real-time wildfire monitoring by integrating NASA VIIRS Satellite data and
 user reports bolstered by AI validation, to enhance early fire detection and promote public awareness.
- Utilized AI for geotagged image analysis, improving rapid wildfire data accuracy by 40%, and showcased active fire trends with a monthly graph. Built using React & TypeScript for frontend and JavaScript & Express for backend.

<u>litmus.tools</u> | TypeScript, React, WebAssembly, JavaScript, Vercel | <u>GitHub</u>

January 2023

- A full-stack geographical tax calculator built using TypeScript, WebAssembly, and React in an aesthetic package.
- Integrated data from the **US National Bureau of Economic Research** to provide users with accurate calculations and insights of their savings, earnings, and taxes, all based on their **individual** ZIP codes.
- Deployed via Vercel's CI/CD pipeline to www.litmus.tools.

afrokk.dev | JavaScript, React, NextJS 13, TypeScript, Sanity CMS, SASS | GitHub

May 2023

- My **full-stack** personal developer portfolio built from scratch to showcase my profile and projects.
- Implemented advanced features like SSR, light/dark mode, lazy loading, custom lightbox, carousels, and scroll bars.

Plus Automobile Dealership DBMS, Airport Simulator (Java), OpenQASM: A Technical Article, Vintage Autohaus, and more.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL (Postgres), HTML/CSS, SASS **Frameworks**: React, Node.js, Flask, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt, Express, Bootstrap, Tailwind **Tools**: Git, Docker, Jira, REST APIs, CI/CD, Adobe Suite, Figma

EXTRA CURRICULARS

NASA Space Apps 2023: Won 1st place at NASA Space Apps 2023 regional competition in a cohort of over 50 teams.

CS Games 2023: Represented uWindsor in Quebec, implemented **cross-platform microservices** for security and data sharing.